Contact

tashelto@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/teokashelton1 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Team Leadership
Organization Skills
Communication

Teoka Shelton, MSN, RN, NEA-BC

Master's in Nursing-Executive Nurse Leadership Houston, Texas

Summary

Becoming a nurse leader merged the 2 things that I love doing. Before choosing nursing as a career, I thought I wanted to be an accountant; I really had a knack for spreadsheets, ledgers, AR and AP. However, after taking an active role in providing care for my maternal grandmother, the love of caring for others totally engulfed me. I never would have imagined that one day my love for budgeting and administration would marry the love of my life, nursing. That's how I envision my role as a nurse leader, the best of both worlds. As an experienced Registered Nurse, I have developed strong clinical and leadership skills since 2001 in various clinical and non -clinical settings. I've acquired extensive knowledge of nursing procedures, processes and leadership through roles as a Staff Nurse, Charge Nurse and Clinical Nurse Manager. Building positive relationships with patients, family members, nurses, physicians and other medical professionals is a priority for me. I am a passionate, servant leader who is committed to excellence in leadership and professional nursing.

In my spare time, I can be found at urban music concerts or happily preparing meals for my family and friends. Their oohh's and aahh's always place a smile on my face. I have recently begun to 'Soul' skate, now that is definitely going to take some time to perfect. Nevertheless, I am falling in love with that activity.

My Nursing Philosophy

Nursing is an art and a science. The role of nursing is to enhance and promote the health of the community. The Profession of Nursing is crucial in how and why the members of the community participate in healthy lifestyles. It is critical for nurses to exhibit compassion, empathy, and sensitivity to all people from different generations and ethnic backgrounds. The nurse must be committed to lifelong learning, developing relationships with patients, families and teams. Last, but not least, the nurse must behave with professionalism and bravery at all times.

Experience

Critical Care Unit
Director
August 2019 - Present (10 months)

Memorial Hermann Health System Clinical Nurse Manager August 2010 - August 2019 (9 years 1 month) Houston, Texas Area

Houston ISD School Nurse March 2009 - June 2010 (1 year 4 months) Lamar High School

Protect and promote student health
Reviewed immunization records
Performed vision, hearing and scoliosis screenings
Health education
First Aid

Administered Medications
Facilitated hospital education for hospitalized students
Occupational Health for staff

Sabine Neches Home Healthcare Supervisor of Nursing January 2008 - May 2009 (1 year 5 months) Bridge City, Texas

Supervised and directed nursing care for home health patients

Ensured agency adhere to governmental and regulatory requirements

Staff training and development

Clinical/documentation audits for compliance and patient needs

Memorial Hermann Health System
Staff Nurse
August 2001 - December 2006 (5 years 5 months)
Houston, Texas Area
Cardiac Cath Lab Holding Area

Med-Surg/Intermediate Care

Charity Hospital of New Orleans Staff Nurse/Charge Nurse January 1998 - December 2001 (4 years)

Greater New Orleans Area

Emergency Center
Emergency Surgery

Education

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston Master's degree, Nursing Science · (2017 - 2019)

Texas Southern University
Health/Health Care Administration/Management · (2004 - 2005)

Willaim Carey College
Bachelor of Science - BS, Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (1994 - 1997)